<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>terraform on Dave Evans</title>
    <link>https://www.daveevans.us/tags/terraform/</link>
    <description>Recent content in terraform on Dave Evans</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 12:39:08 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.daveevans.us/tags/terraform/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CI Build System with Terraform, Anisble, and Jenkins</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/ci-build-system-with-terraform-ansible-jenkins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 12:39:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/ci-build-system-with-terraform-ansible-jenkins/</guid>
      <description>In the first part of this series, I described some of the goals for moving our organization to using Infrastructure as Code processes. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to describe the setup that was created to have a server build pipeline for on premise deployments of Virtual Servers. However, I feel the strength of this approach is its ability to be extended to application deployments on top of these server builds, and the possibilty to have the same setup on any cloud of your choosing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Journey to Infrastructure as Code - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/my-journey-to-infrastructure-as-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 08:24:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/my-journey-to-infrastructure-as-code/</guid>
      <description>This is the first part of a multipart series on how I introduced Infrastructure as Code(IaC) processes to my organization. My end goal is to implement a complete IaC pipeline from image build to deployment of infrastructure, but we are an organization that needs to go through a bit of a transformation and need to take this journey in small incremental steps. We have a very on-premises bias to our systems due to strict compliance regulations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pure Storage Guest Blog</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/pure-storage-guestblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 20:55:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/pure-storage-guestblog/</guid>
      <description>This blog was originally posted on the Pure Storage Blog
For the last couple months, I have been working on some side projects to work with Pure Storage. These projects gave me the opportunity to learn golang and learn more about code development, testing, and even some continuous integration. The links to these projects are on my github, and on the Projects page of this site.
I began to take a look at Terraform to use within our environment for infrastructure deployments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying My Blog on Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/deploying-my-blog-on-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 21:58:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/deploying-my-blog-on-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>So its been quite awhile since I posted anything. That is because I have been very busy with some personal projects and doing a lot of studying of some new technologies.
As you can see I have completely redone my site. The previous site was running on the Ghost platform, which was spun up using a one-click deployment from DigitalOcean. Ghost was a good platform. I liked doing the posts in markdown, and it was easy to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform Provider for PureStorage FlashArray</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/terraform-provider-for-purestorage-flasharray/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/terraform-provider-for-purestorage-flasharray/</guid>
      <description>About a month and a half ago, I began to take a look at Terraform to use within our environment for infrastructure deployments. The goal was twofold. First, have a way to perform scripted, template style deployments using an Infrastructure-as-code philosophy. Second, to be able to use the same tool across multiple platforms both on-prem (VMWare, OracleVM, and FlashStack) and in the cloud (AWS and Azure).
What is Terraform? From the terraform.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>