<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IaC on Dave Evans</title>
    <link>https://www.daveevans.us/tags/iac/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IaC on Dave Evans</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 20:12:03 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.daveevans.us/tags/iac/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>OVM Terraform Provider</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/ovm-terraform-provider/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 20:12:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/ovm-terraform-provider/</guid>
      <description>Oracle VM 3(OVM) is the original vituralization solution from everybody&amp;rsquo;s favorite software company. I say &amp;ldquo;original&amp;rdquo; because last year they completely replaced the solution with a new version. The new solution, Oracle Linux Virtualization Manager is based on the upstream oVirt project and utilizes KVM for its hypervisor. Oracle VM utilizes the Xen hypervisor, so any migration to the new version will require a rebuild of the virtual environment and a migration of the virtual machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Packer to Build VM Templates for Oracle VM 3</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/packer-ovm-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 09:52:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/packer-ovm-templates/</guid>
      <description>Anyone that has had the pleasure of running Oracle VM 3(OVM3) has most likely struggled with of the lack of integrations with 3rd party tools and features compared to other hypervisors. For example, there are no live snapshot capabilities and there is no agentless backup solution. It seems that Oracle has not put much development into Oracle VM over the years, and with the release of Oracle VM 4, which is a fork of the upstream oVirt project, OVM3 is most likely near its End-of-Life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Journey to Infrastructure as Code - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/my-journey-to-infrastructure-as-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 08:24:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/my-journey-to-infrastructure-as-code/</guid>
      <description>This is the first part of a multipart series on how I introduced Infrastructure as Code(IaC) processes to my organization. My end goal is to implement a complete IaC pipeline from image build to deployment of infrastructure, but we are an organization that needs to go through a bit of a transformation and need to take this journey in small incremental steps. We have a very on-premises bias to our systems due to strict compliance regulations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
