<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>raspberry pi on Dave Evans</title>
    <link>https://www.daveevans.us/tags/raspberry-pi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in raspberry pi on Dave Evans</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 01:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.daveevans.us/tags/raspberry-pi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes on Raspberry Pi, The Hard Way - Part 5</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/kubernetes-on-raspberry-pi-the-hard-way-part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/kubernetes-on-raspberry-pi-the-hard-way-part-5/</guid>
      <description>Kubernetes on Raspberry Pi, The Hard Way - Part 1 Kubernetes on Raspberry Pi, The Hard Way - Part 2 Kubernetes on Raspberry Pi, The Hard Way - Part 3 Kubernetes on Raspberry Pi, The Hard Way - Part 4  The final part of this journey is to setup the networking. Which in the end is pretty straight forward, but did cause me some grief. I had trouble getting kube-dns working.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes on Raspberry Pi, The Hard Way - Part 4</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/kubernetes-on-raspberry-pi-the-hard-way-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/kubernetes-on-raspberry-pi-the-hard-way-part-4/</guid>
      <description>Kubernetes on Raspberry Pi, The Hard Way - Part 1 Kubernetes on Raspberry Pi, The Hard Way - Part 2 Kubernetes on Raspberry Pi, The Hard Way - Part 3  Now its time to setup the worker nodes. This is where I will deviate the most from the original Kubernetes the Hard Way, as I plan to change the container runtime from containerd to docker.
Install and Configure Docker These commands should be run on each worker node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes on Raspberry Pi, The Hard Way - Part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/kubernetes-on-raspberry-pi-the-hard-way-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/kubernetes-on-raspberry-pi-the-hard-way-part-3/</guid>
      <description>Kubernetes on Raspberry Pi, The Hard Way - Part 1 Kubernetes on Raspberry Pi, The Hard Way - Part 2  In this part of the series, we will setup the 3 master nodes. Starting by installing the Ectd, then the kube-apiserver, kube-controller-manager, and kube-scheduler. In a bit of a departure from the original Kubernetes the Hard Way, I will not setup the the local nginx proxy on each master node to proxy the healthz endpoint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes on Raspberry Pi, The Hard Way - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/kubernetes-on-raspberry-pi-the-hard-way-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/kubernetes-on-raspberry-pi-the-hard-way-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Kubernetes on Raspberry Pi, The Hard Way - Part 1
Now the fun begins&amp;hellip;
After the setup of the raspberry pi servers in part 1, I have the hostnames and IPs in the table below. We now have to create a CA and certificates for all the different pieces of the cluster. Then create kubeconfigs for the different components to use to connect to the cluster, and distribute everything out to the nodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes on Raspberry Pi, The Hard Way - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/kubernetes-on-raspberry-pi-the-hard-way-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/kubernetes-on-raspberry-pi-the-hard-way-part-1/</guid>
      <description>There are SO many blog posts about installing a Kubernetes cluster on Raspberry Pi, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to be left out.
I have been playing around with Kubernetes for a couple months now. I have setup MiniKube and OpenShift on a Single Fedora Node that runs on a Mac Mini. I&amp;rsquo;ve taken the Certified Kubernetes Administrator course on Linux Academy, which sets up a small cluster, and I have just finished The Linux Academy course Kubernetes the Hard Way, which follows Kelsey Hightower&amp;rsquo;s paper Kubernetes The Hard Way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
