<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dave Evans</title>
    <link>https://www.daveevans.us/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dave Evans</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 09:39:21 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.daveevans.us/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Goals</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/personal/goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 09:39:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/personal/goals/</guid>
      <description>August 15 - 21       Goal Sun Mon Tues Wed Thur Fri Sat Met     Lose 2 lbs. 248 249 249 247 245      10 push up challenge X X X X X      NRC Week 2  X  X        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Direction</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/personal/a-new-direction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 08:03:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/personal/a-new-direction/</guid>
      <description>So it has been quite a while since I posted anything here. Not that I have ever been at a fast and furious pace of content creation, but almost a year since my last post is a bit much. Looking at the date of my last post I can begin to understand why. This blog is going to take a bit of a more personal turn. Mainly because that is what I have been working on&amp;hellip; me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OVM Terraform Provider</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/ovm-terraform-provider/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 20:12:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/ovm-terraform-provider/</guid>
      <description>Oracle VM 3(OVM) is the original vituralization solution from everybody&amp;rsquo;s favorite software company. I say &amp;ldquo;original&amp;rdquo; because last year they completely replaced the solution with a new version. The new solution, Oracle Linux Virtualization Manager is based on the upstream oVirt project and utilizes KVM for its hypervisor. Oracle VM utilizes the Xen hypervisor, so any migration to the new version will require a rebuild of the virtual environment and a migration of the virtual machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Packer to Build VM Templates for Oracle VM 3</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/packer-ovm-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 09:52:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/packer-ovm-templates/</guid>
      <description>Anyone that has had the pleasure of running Oracle VM 3(OVM3) has most likely struggled with of the lack of integrations with 3rd party tools and features compared to other hypervisors. For example, there are no live snapshot capabilities and there is no agentless backup solution. It seems that Oracle has not put much development into Oracle VM over the years, and with the release of Oracle VM 4, which is a fork of the upstream oVirt project, OVM3 is most likely near its End-of-Life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CI Build System with Terraform, Anisble, and Jenkins</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/ci-build-system-with-terraform-ansible-jenkins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 12:39:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/ci-build-system-with-terraform-ansible-jenkins/</guid>
      <description>In the first part of this series, I described some of the goals for moving our organization to using Infrastructure as Code processes. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to describe the setup that was created to have a server build pipeline for on premise deployments of Virtual Servers. However, I feel the strength of this approach is its ability to be extended to application deployments on top of these server builds, and the possibilty to have the same setup on any cloud of your choosing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Journey to Infrastructure as Code - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/my-journey-to-infrastructure-as-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 08:24:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/my-journey-to-infrastructure-as-code/</guid>
      <description>This is the first part of a multipart series on how I introduced Infrastructure as Code(IaC) processes to my organization. My end goal is to implement a complete IaC pipeline from image build to deployment of infrastructure, but we are an organization that needs to go through a bit of a transformation and need to take this journey in small incremental steps. We have a very on-premises bias to our systems due to strict compliance regulations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pure Storage Guest Blog</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/pure-storage-guestblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 20:55:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/pure-storage-guestblog/</guid>
      <description>This blog was originally posted on the Pure Storage Blog
For the last couple months, I have been working on some side projects to work with Pure Storage. These projects gave me the opportunity to learn golang and learn more about code development, testing, and even some continuous integration. The links to these projects are on my github, and on the Projects page of this site.
I began to take a look at Terraform to use within our environment for infrastructure deployments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Nginx Ingress Controller</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/kubernetes-nginx-ingress-controller/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 15:43:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/kubernetes-nginx-ingress-controller/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post, I deployed my website on a Kubernetes cluster running on DigitalOcean. However, I still would like to decrease my costs as much as possible. The original setup used a Digital Ocean LoadBalancer instance as the Ingress to the Kubernetes Pods. This works great and is very easy to setup with Terraform. However, there are a couple downsides to this setup. At this time, the Kubernetes ingress objects cannot take advantage of Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt integration with the DigitalOcean LoadBalancer instances, and the solution will end up being a bit pricey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying My Blog on Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/deploying-my-blog-on-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 21:58:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/deploying-my-blog-on-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>So its been quite awhile since I posted anything. That is because I have been very busy with some personal projects and doing a lot of studying of some new technologies.
As you can see I have completely redone my site. The previous site was running on the Ghost platform, which was spun up using a one-click deployment from DigitalOcean. Ghost was a good platform. I liked doing the posts in markdown, and it was easy to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 20:53:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/projects/</guid>
      <description>Terraform Provider for Flash     Project Site Github Repository  PuGo     Golang library for interacting with the Pure Storage APIs. Currently, has packages for FlashArray and Pure1 Github Repository  Terraform Provider for OVM     Github Repository Terraform Registry  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 18:09:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/resume/</guid>
      <description>Profile     I am a well-seasoned Infrastructure Engineer with professional experience with a variety of technologies in large scale environments. A passion for learning drives me to continually explore new technology both professionally and personally. I enjoy the challenge of creating secure, stable, and functional systems and applications, and solving all the problems that arise during the development life cycle.
Professional Experience     Duquesne Light Company    May 2020 - Present    Principal Architect     Responsible for developing a DevOps strategy for the IT organization Develop a CI/CD architecture that can be utilized to streamline project delivery and operations  March 2015 – May 2020    Infrastructure Engineer IV     Administer RedHat Linux 5, 6, and 7 environment of over 425 servers Developed a Cofiguration Management system using Puppet Created custom puppet modules for deploying applications within our environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 18:08:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been in varying levels of systems administration for over a decade. I started in applications and middleware, and eventually settled into Infrastructure, hardware, and Linux administration. I have a strong passion for creating and learning about computer systems, especially large scale distributed applications.
Github Page
GitLab Page
Resume</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes on Raspberry Pi, The Hard Way - Part 5</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/kubernetes-on-raspberry-pi-the-hard-way-part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/kubernetes-on-raspberry-pi-the-hard-way-part-5/</guid>
      <description>Kubernetes on Raspberry Pi, The Hard Way - Part 1 Kubernetes on Raspberry Pi, The Hard Way - Part 2 Kubernetes on Raspberry Pi, The Hard Way - Part 3 Kubernetes on Raspberry Pi, The Hard Way - Part 4  The final part of this journey is to setup the networking. Which in the end is pretty straight forward, but did cause me some grief. I had trouble getting kube-dns working.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes on Raspberry Pi, The Hard Way - Part 4</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/kubernetes-on-raspberry-pi-the-hard-way-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/kubernetes-on-raspberry-pi-the-hard-way-part-4/</guid>
      <description>Kubernetes on Raspberry Pi, The Hard Way - Part 1 Kubernetes on Raspberry Pi, The Hard Way - Part 2 Kubernetes on Raspberry Pi, The Hard Way - Part 3  Now its time to setup the worker nodes. This is where I will deviate the most from the original Kubernetes the Hard Way, as I plan to change the container runtime from containerd to docker.
Install and Configure Docker    These commands should be run on each worker node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes on Raspberry Pi, The Hard Way - Part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/kubernetes-on-raspberry-pi-the-hard-way-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/kubernetes-on-raspberry-pi-the-hard-way-part-3/</guid>
      <description>Kubernetes on Raspberry Pi, The Hard Way - Part 1 Kubernetes on Raspberry Pi, The Hard Way - Part 2  In this part of the series, we will setup the 3 master nodes. Starting by installing the Ectd, then the kube-apiserver, kube-controller-manager, and kube-scheduler. In a bit of a departure from the original Kubernetes the Hard Way, I will not setup the the local nginx proxy on each master node to proxy the healthz endpoint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes on Raspberry Pi, The Hard Way - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/kubernetes-on-raspberry-pi-the-hard-way-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/kubernetes-on-raspberry-pi-the-hard-way-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Kubernetes on Raspberry Pi, The Hard Way - Part 1
Now the fun begins&amp;hellip;
After the setup of the raspberry pi servers in part 1, I have the hostnames and IPs in the table below. We now have to create a CA and certificates for all the different pieces of the cluster. Then create kubeconfigs for the different components to use to connect to the cluster, and distribute everything out to the nodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes on Raspberry Pi, The Hard Way - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/kubernetes-on-raspberry-pi-the-hard-way-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/kubernetes-on-raspberry-pi-the-hard-way-part-1/</guid>
      <description>There are SO many blog posts about installing a Kubernetes cluster on Raspberry Pi, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to be left out.
I have been playing around with Kubernetes for a couple months now. I have setup MiniKube and OpenShift on a Single Fedora Node that runs on a Mac Mini. I&amp;rsquo;ve taken the Certified Kubernetes Administrator course on Linux Academy, which sets up a small cluster, and I have just finished The Linux Academy course Kubernetes the Hard Way, which follows Kelsey Hightower&amp;rsquo;s paper Kubernetes The Hard Way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Life of a Network Packet in Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/the-life-of-a-network-packet-in-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/the-life-of-a-network-packet-in-linux/</guid>
      <description>I have encountered this problem numerous times, and every time I am told &amp;ldquo;There is something wrong with the network!!&amp;rdquo;
What I really need is someone much more creative than me to write a children&amp;rsquo;s song similar to Schoolhouse Rock&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m Just a Bill&amp;rdquo;, except for network packets
Scenario    There are 2 servers. Each server has 2 network interfaces that all have listening addresses in separate subnets. The Default route for each server is via eth0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a Python Project</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/setting-up-a-python-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/setting-up-a-python-project/</guid>
      <description>I have been writing Python code for probably close to 10 years. The crazy part about this is that I am completely self-taught in Python didn&amp;rsquo;t know any &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; way to do things. Basically, as a Systems Administrator, I was writing shell scripts, and as I came upon problems that required some more advanced features, I would switch to writing in Python. More specifically, as I needed to interact with both WebLogic and WebSphere, I had to write code using the Python/Jython libraries that shipped with those products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Kubernetes on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/deploying-kubernetes-on-aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/deploying-kubernetes-on-aws/</guid>
      <description>Ok, yes, I know that I can use EKS for running containers on AWS, or any number of KaaS or hosted solutions, but none of that is any fun. I know. I have an odd definition of fun.
Anyway, my goal here is to standup a Kubernetes cluster on AWS. I just passed my first AWS Certification, and I want some things to practice on. This will probably actually end up as more of a series of posts, as I want to learn CloudFormation, mess with the RDS instances, and eventually probably move this blog over to AWS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My New Favorite Tool... ncdu</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/my-new-favorite-tool-ncdu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/my-new-favorite-tool-ncdu/</guid>
      <description>So today I found my new favorite command line tool, ncdu. This is a ncurses disk utilization tool that is great for finding what is filling up your file systems. Especially on servers that do not have a graphical interface.
If you are like me, when I get file system alerts, it was an endless string of &amp;lsquo;du -h &amp;ndash;max-depth=1&amp;rsquo; commands. I would have to re-run that command as I drilled down through the directory structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using QOwnNotes with NextCloud</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/using-qownnotes-with-nextcloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/using-qownnotes-with-nextcloud/</guid>
      <description>The next part of this migration is something that is a LONG time coming, replacing Evernote. However, this isn&amp;rsquo;t quite a migration. I had stopped using Evernote a few years ago, when I had switched my daily driver to Linux. Most of my data that was previously in Evernote, I had exported to folders in my Dropbox, but while I kept it, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really use it anymore.
Most of my note taking has reverted to just text files that reside spread across my Documents directory, and I have no good way of organizing them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating to NextCloud, Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/migration-to-nextcloud-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/migration-to-nextcloud-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Previous Post
As I found out shortly after my last post about migrating to NextCloud. Not all of my data transferred successfully. However, this was not NextClouds fault. The short version is that I was allowing the NextCloud iOS client to upload my photos through my iPhone. The problem happened as the original(aka, non-optimized) photos were downloaded from iCloud then uploaded to NextCloud. As more photos came down, I ran out of space on my iPhone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using OpenSCAP for Security Patch Validation</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/using-openscap-for-security-patch-validation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/using-openscap-for-security-patch-validation/</guid>
      <description>I have been looking for a way to validate patches in my environment. This validation need to occur outside of the patch repository, because what if the repository is incomplete. This may seem like overkill (and it probably is), but the validation was really more about creating verifiable evidence that patching had occurred and everything was applied.
My environment consists completely of Red Hat and Red Hat derivative distributions, so most of this will apply to those, but some may be applicable to other distributions as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving from Dropbox to Nextcloud</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/moving-from-dropbox-to-nextcloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/moving-from-dropbox-to-nextcloud/</guid>
      <description>Last week I got a notification on my desktop that as of November 7, 2018 Dropbox will stop syncing files to my computer. They are making a change to only support the “most popular filesystems”, and on Linux that means only unencrypted ext4. Unfortunately, I use XFS on all of my machines, and I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like duct taping solution together. Besides, I have been looking for a reason to move off of Dropbox, and this just gave me the push to move forward.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
