<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ansible on Dave Evans</title>
    <link>https://www.daveevans.us/tags/ansible/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ansible on Dave Evans</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 12:39:08 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.daveevans.us/tags/ansible/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CI Build System with Terraform, Anisble, and Jenkins</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/ci-build-system-with-terraform-ansible-jenkins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 12:39:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/ci-build-system-with-terraform-ansible-jenkins/</guid>
      <description>In the first part of this series, I described some of the goals for moving our organization to using Infrastructure as Code processes. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to describe the setup that was created to have a server build pipeline for on premise deployments of Virtual Servers. However, I feel the strength of this approach is its ability to be extended to application deployments on top of these server builds, and the possibilty to have the same setup on any cloud of your choosing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Journey to Infrastructure as Code - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/my-journey-to-infrastructure-as-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 08:24:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.daveevans.us/posts/my-journey-to-infrastructure-as-code/</guid>
      <description>This is the first part of a multipart series on how I introduced Infrastructure as Code(IaC) processes to my organization. My end goal is to implement a complete IaC pipeline from image build to deployment of infrastructure, but we are an organization that needs to go through a bit of a transformation and need to take this journey in small incremental steps. We have a very on-premises bias to our systems due to strict compliance regulations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
